<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Odyssey Shuttle Variants</name>
  <author>Luke</author>
  <packageId>luke.odysseyshuttlevariants</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>Expands RimWorld's Odyssey transport-shuttle system with a family of buildable, role-distinct craft and a typed-capacity system that tracks colonists, mechs and cargo as independent pools instead of one shared mass limit. Multiplayer-compatible.

THE CRAFT
- Passenger Shuttle (vanilla, folded into the system) - the balanced all-rounder: a handful of seats and modest cargo.
- Troop Shuttle - fast squad insertion and extraction: many seats, light cargo, long range.
- Cargo Shuttle - dedicated hauler: a large hold with just enough crew to fly it.
- Heavy Cargo Ship - the flagship hauler: the biggest hold in the fleet, but slow, fuel-hungry and short-ranged.
- Mechanitor Shuttle (Biotech) - a mech strike carrier flown by a mechanitor; it will not launch without one aboard. It ferries a mech warband against a bandwidth budget rather than a seat count. When landed it also doubles as a chemfuel-powered field charger: nearby colony mechs walk up to the hull and recharge from the shuttle's own fuel, no power grid required (an opt-in toggle, off by default so it never strands itself).
- Transport Drone (Biotech) - a fully autonomous courier with no crew. Send it anywhere, land and hold its cargo in the field, then recall it, send it onward, form a camp, or gift its cargo to a friendly settlement for goodwill.

FEATURES
- Typed capacity: colonists (seats), mechs (bandwidth budget) and cargo (mass, excluding crew and mech weight) are capped independently, with clear load-dialog readouts and over-cap warnings.
- Autonomous drone: hands-free supply runs and automated diplomacy gifts; it survives the origin map being abandoned.
- Mech field charging at a landed Mechanitor Shuttle, run off its own chemfuel.
- Mech-bay expansion research: two tiers that raise the Mechanitor Shuttle's carried-mech bandwidth (6 to 12 to 18) and widen its field-charging line (2 to 3 to 4 mechs at once). Already-built ships benefit the moment the research completes.
- Every craft is research-gated off the vanilla Shuttles project, built in the Odyssey architect category, and costs a rare shuttle engine (trader/reward only; larger craft need more).

MULTIPLAYER
Built with the Multiplayer mod and tested in multiplayer sessions with no issues found. It also runs fine without Multiplayer installed.
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2606448745

Requires Odyssey. The Mechanitor Shuttle and Transport Drone additionally require Biotech.

Portions of the materials used to create this content/mod are trademarks and/or copyrighted works of Ludeon Studios Inc. All rights reserved by Ludeon. This content/mod is not official and is not endorsed by Ludeon.</description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</packageId>
      <displayName>Odyssey</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</li>
    <!-- Optional: when present, load after Multiplayer so its API is initialized before our
         StaticConstructorOnStartup registers sync methods. Not a dependency - the mod runs fine
         without Multiplayer (the API stub reports MP.enabled = false). -->
    <li>rwmt.Multiplayer</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
